Communication channels.
So communication involves body language.
I've mentioned this over and over and
over.
Body language is the major part of
communications.
Voice inflection, that's
paralegal, the words we use,
gestures, facial expression
are all ways we communicate.
Let's talk about the number of
communication channels.
So the formula itself is n times n minus
one divided by two.
So n is the number of stakeholders
involved.
So an example here, if there are four
people, four times three divided by two,
you have six lines of communication.
If there are 10 people, you end up with 45
lines of communication.
The whole reason they want you to
understand this.
They want you to remember, it's not just
you sending out information communicating.
They will communicate back to you and to
each other.
So the more stakeholders
involved, the more
like a spider web it ends up looking like.
So something to keep in mind.
Let's note this.
Read the question carefully to determine
whether you are included in the team or
you must add yourself or stakeholders
might not just always be the team okay so
an example you're managing five people
that means n is six you must add yourself
if your team has five five people you are
already part of the team so n is five so
read the questions carefully and slowly
there are five stakeholders and is five
you're communicating with five and is six
you have to add yourself so just read it
carefully sometimes they'll say people
will come and go some stakeholders will be
added some will be deleted and they'll ask
you the difference how many additional
channels of communication
there are, which means you have
to know how many you start
with and how many you end with.
The difference is the number of additional
communication channels.
So just read it carefully, very,
very easy formula, but also important.